# Asish Raz

Patna, Bihar, India



iamasish3001@gmail.com



+91-6360573539



linkedin.com/in/asish-raz-75b38411b

## **Summary**

Front-End Developer with over 3 years of experience in the IT Industry.

Huge interests in web-designing with sheer knowledge of CSS and JS

The tendency of solving problems with the programming mindset

Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction.

## **Experience**



## Python Developer

ΕY

Dec 2019 - 2021 (2 years 1 month)

Coordinated with the development team to discuss user-interface ideas and applications

Worked with business and design requirements to develop web pages.

Collaborated with the back-end team to implement solutions that are aligned with and extend shared platforms and solutions

Developed the logic for extracting the data from the PDF using python.

#### VOLVO VOLVO SASSE

## **Software Developer**

Volvo Group

Jan 2019 - Jul 2019 (7 months)

Used the built-in react-toolkit to build user-facing features Added new functionality, and event handling to the existing modules

Created, maintained, and enforced front-end code and documentation standards

Perform bug-fixing and implement HTML templates Built reusable code for future use and optimized web pages for better scalability



#### **Developer cum Core Member**

Humble Innovations Private Limited Nov 2016 - Oct 2018 (2 years) A full-fledged Quality Control and Management System for Public Toilets with Feedback, Monitoring, and Component Modules

Built performance reports notification to enable the authorities for identifying and encourage janitors for their work

Design a scalable app architecture as well as the APIs to support it continuously Used React components for different use cases Perform Bug Fixing A core member of the Startup

## **Education**



## Orissa Engineering College (OEC), Bhubaneswar

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Information Technology 2012 - 2016 persuade the degree of B.Tech in the year 2016 participated in the singing competition in the very first year...



## Loyola High School, Patna

Science 2000 - 2012

## **Skills**

HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • React.js • Python (Programming Language) • Bootstrap • Vue.js • Django • Flask • REST APIs